thetechlounge.com 2019-03-13

# Privacy Policy - The Tech Lounge

Effective Date: May 24, 2018

**Please, Review this Privacy Policy carefully before using the website (TheTechLounge.com)**

TheTechLounge.com (“TheTechLounge”, “Site”, “we”, “us” or “our”) values the privacy of our website visitors and individuals whose personal information we receive through form submissions and other related services.

The Privacy Policy describes what data we collect, how we use it and steps we take to protect this information.

**By visiting or using this website, you agree to this Privacy Policy.**

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through this Site. It does not apply to information that you may provide by any other means or any third-party sites we link to. This Privacy Policy applies to all devices that can be used to access the Site.

### What information do we collect

#### User-provided Information

We may collect Personal Information including (but not limited to) your full name and email when you use our website. We may require you to provide Personal Information when you leave a comment, submit contact form or opt for a newsletter.

For example, when visitors leave comments on the Site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

#### Passively or Automatically Collected Information

We automatically collect certain information when you access our Site using various technologies like cookies, “clear gifs”, “web beacons” or scripts. The information may include your IP address, web browser, device type, system type, the content and pages you visited while interacting with our Site, dates and times of the visit, demographic data such as age, additional data regarding your use of the website (time on site, number of viewed pages, clicks, etc.). 

#### What cookies do we use

Cookie is a small piece of data sent from a website and stored on the user’s computer by the user’s web browser while the user is browsing. Cookies were designed to be a reliable mechanism for websites to remember information about the user or to record the user’s browsing activity. Cookies can also be used to remember pieces of information that the user previously entered into form fields such as names, addresses, passwords etc.

Strictly necessary cookies – These cookies are required for our website operations. They help us serve you information in a secure and optimal way.

Performance cookies – These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website (visited pages, time on site, etc.). These cookies do not collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and anonymous. We use this information to improve the website so you can easily navigate through it and find necessary information.

Functionality cookies – These cookies are not essential but they allow the website to remember choices you make and provide a better-tailored experience for you. For example, if you leave a comment on our Site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

Social media cookies – These cookies are used when you use social media features available through the Site (e.g. clicking on the “Like” or “Share” icon on a webpage). Social Media plugins may collect your IP address and the page you were visiting at out Site and set cookies to provide the necessary functionality. Your interactions with these services are subject to Privacy Policy of the feature provider.

Advertising cookies – These cookies collect web browsing activity information and may be used to provide targeted advertisements based on previous browsing activity.

You can control cookies on the personal level and edit the cookies settings in your browser.

### How we use your information

We may use personal information to operate, provide, improve, and maintain the TheTechLounge; to prevent abusive and fraudulent use of the TheTechLounge; to personalize and display content on the TheTechLounge; to send you information (via email) in which we think you may be interested; to respond to your inquiries and for other customer service purposes; and for other administrative and internal business purposes.

On the TheTechLounge, we may use passively collected data to: (a) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Site; and (b) monitor aggregate website usage metrics such as a total number of visitors, pages viewed etc..

In addition, we use Google Analytics to analyze our users’ behavior on TheTechLounge. Google Analytics provides us with aggregated data in order to help us make informed business decisions. Ultimately, Google, as a third party, controls information collected through Google Analytics and you should check and be comfortable with its privacy practices prior to using the TheTechLounge. You may review information about Google’s privacy practices at <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>. You can opt out from Google Analytics by using this [link](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

### Disclosure of Collected Information

TheTechLounge will not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to others. Any information that you voluntarily choose to include in a Public Area of the Site becomes publicly available and may be collected and used by us or others without restriction.

#### Service Providers

Third party service providers who provide us website development, hosting, maintenance, security, data analysis, database management and other services may have access to personal information. We limit the information provided to third-party services providers to absolutely necessary for them to provide their functions. We require all third party service providers to agree to use your personal information only in accordance to this Privacy Policy.

#### Non Personally Identifiable And Aggregated Information

We may use and share aggregated non personally identifiable information for reporting, business or marketing purposes (demonstrate the usage of our services, show trends, etc.).

#### Legal Requirements

We may disclosure your personal information if we are required to do so by law and if we believe that such action is necessary to protect the rights, property and safety of the TheTechLounge, our users or other individuals; maintain and protect the security and integrity of our Site; protect our Site from fraudulent uses or assist government enforcement agencies.

#### Change of Ownership

If we decide to sell/transfer/merge our Site, personal information can be transferred to acquirer, successor or assignee as a result of any merger, acquisition or similar operation.

#### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.  
If you believe your rights or privacy has been infringed or want to delete certain personal information contact us at contact@thetechlounge.com. To access the information the Site stored about you (and send an anonymization request) use this form.

### Where we send your data

Information collected through the TheTechLounge may be stored and processed in the United States, Europe or other countries where our partners or services we use (hosting or other third-party services) are operating.

### Third-Party Services

The TheTechLounge may contain links to third-party sites and services. We are not responsible for policies of third-party sites or services to whom we link, and all information you provide to third party sites or services is subject to those services policies.

We also may receive information from third-party service providers like network advertisers and analytics providers to evaluate our marketing efforts and tailor marketing/advertising campaigns.

Some third-party extensions used on the Site (i.e. Social Share functionality, Amazon Affiliate plugins), may automatically collect information like your IP, location, page on our website where you engaged with third-party functionality, etc. and store cookies. Your interactions with these services are subject to Privacy Policy of the feature provider.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this Site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.  
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. Google Analytics stores your data for 26 months.

### How we protect your data

Your security is important to us and we use various security measures to keep your information (including personal information) safe using (but not limited to) the firewalls and encryption.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

In case of the data breach, we will attempt to notify you by email with the instructions and steps you should take to protect your data. Also, if the security breach takes place, we may post a notice on our homepage.

### Children

The Site is not directed to children under the age of 13. If you are under 13, you shouldn’t use our Site or send any personal information to us. We do not knowingly collect or maintain personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If we learn that personal information from a user under 13 has been collected on our Site, we will take steps to delete this information.

### Your California Privacy Rights

We don’t share any personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes according to the California law. If our practices change we will notify you and act in accordance with applicable laws.

### Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. All changes to this Privacy Policy become effective the moment they are posted. If we change the Privacy Policy, we will change the “effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay up-to-date with any changes.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or your Personal Information, you can contact us at contact@thetechlounge.com
